

 \checkmark

4rkasengupta@gmail.com



+91 8335078313



Bangalore, India



arkasengupta.github.io/Portfolio



linkedin.com/in/arka--sengupta



github.com/ArkaSengupta

SKILLS

Python

AWS

React IS

JavaScript

Spring Boot

Java

Machine Learning

Angular

Django

MvSOL

AWS KMS

NI P

Matplotlib

Jupyter Notebook

Big Data

Automation

Kubernetes

Docker

Data Science

Git

INTERESTS

Portfolio Management & Trading – Binance & Kucoin

Calisthenics

Chess

Arka Sengupta

Software Engineer - PayU Payments | B.E. (IT) - Jadavpur University

Experienced Software Developer with in depth knowledge of a large payment gateway. Proficient in Python Scripts, Client Integrations, Product Improvements and Security Enhancements in ReactJS (JavaScript) and Spring Boot (Java) Applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Software Engineer PayU Payments Pvt. Ltd.

07/2023 - Present

Bangalore, India

- Executed data encryption projects with a strong focus on privacy compliance, integrating AWS services such as KMS (Key Management Service) and AWS Secrets Manager, leading to a successful deal closure with a Fortune 10 client
- Developed a Python Script to automate a data transformation assignment to transfer around 2.5 billion transaction data.
- Designed and developed a role based authorization functionality and an audit history management system for Admin portal.
- Collaborated with banking clients to gather requirements, address issues, and deliver tailored solutions.
- Successfully completed 350+ security enhancements and fixed several vulnerability issues detected by comprehensive security code review of the portals.
- Built a Django application for backend authentication, integrated it with a Spring Boot backend and MySQL database, and deployed the solution on AWS for a new beta product.

Software Engineer Intern PayU Payments Pvt. Ltd.

01/2023 - 07/2023

Bangalore, India

- Resolved critical last-minute client onboarding issues by fixing several vulnerabilities and implementing comprehensive validation checks
- Conducted thorough troubleshooting and implemented multiple fixes to address integration challenges with third-party software.
- Made several improvements in React and Angular Dashboards with Spring Boot Backends.

Machine Learning Intern Perfios Software Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

01/2022 - 03/2022

Bangalore, India

Developed an error detection module in Python to evaluate OCR output, leveraging NLP (Natural Language Processing) techniques to reduce manual processing time by 80% through data analysis and text-vector evaluation.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Engineering - Information TechnologyJadavpur University

06/2019 - 05/2023

First Class With Honours

- Received Honours in Automata and Compiler, Big Data, Network Security, Pattern recognition and Application, Data Science, NLP and Text Mining.
- Completed a research paper on "A Deep Learning based Framework for Detecting Depression from Electroencephalogram biomarkers".

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACHIEVEMENTS

National School Chess Champion U-17 (2018)

World School Chess Championship U-17 Top 22 Qualified (2018)

National University Teams Chess Champion (2019)